JOE: How can we adapt our communication
style to meet the needs and preferences
of each individual with autism.
BETH: When communicating with individuals
with autism it is important to remember
each person is unique and has unique needs
and preferences and these are not going
to be obvious straight away but there
are different approaches we can take.
People should be aware of their
communication style and how
much spoken language they use.
By modifying this using clear,
simplified instructions, or giving
extra processing time before repeating
something or expecting an answer can help.
JOE: Being specific with questions can
make answering easier or describing
objects specifically such as
including the size or the colour of
something make it easier to identify.
BETH: Giving instructions in order,
can help to make the process of doing
something much clearer, for example
when talking to a child by saying ‘First
put your shoes on, then pick up your
bag’ this helps them to understand
the order in which to do things.
JOE: Let’s now hear an
individuals own experience.